eham.net 2019-03-30

# eHam.net Privacy Statement

Updated 26-Feb-2004

eHam.net has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. We recognize that our members are our most important asset, and we strive to protect their interests at all times. We commit to keeping individual and community interests paramount and protecting the confidentiality of our members. We avoid asking for information from our members, unless we feel it is necessary for security or we feel the information is necessary for the application. Any information supplied to us by our members will not be sold or offered to any third party without the express written consent of our members.

Since privacy is so important to us, we will always give you an opportunity to view, change, or delete certain personal information (see callbook) that we gather from you. This information is stored to improve your eHam.net experience, and is in no way used by the site owners, advertisers, or anyone else but you. 

Please realize that eHam.net is NOT ham radio, but a website and as such, does not and cannot follow the same rules. Users do NOT have to use legitimate callsigns to log in, your words are permanently available for all to see, and DX doesn't count for any awards. 

## Cookies

The use of HTML cookies is now optional. Please read our updated FAQ page. Basically, we use them for security so that other members cannot post information on the site with your Callsign and to allow users to come back to the site without having to sign in again. Signing in has its benefits. 

## Public Forums

This site makes various forums available to its members. Please remember that anything that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information, or points of view. Posts will be subject to rebuttal by other members, some of it aggressive in nature. Keep in mind, they are your words, and they can be used against you!

In general, we are reluctant to delete any posts as doing so potentially disturbs the continuity of the thread. We will do so, and without warning, if the posts are deemed undesirable by the eHam.net staff.

## Callbook

One aspect of Amateur Radio that is different from many other pursuits is that it requires a license from a government authority. In the USA, for example, this is the [FCC](http://www.fcc.gov/).

The name and address (callbook) information of US hams displayed on eHam.net is in the public domain and downloaded directly from the FCC site on a regular basis. It is eHam.net's policy to provide this information as a service to our users and hams around the world who often use this information for QSLing. We cannot edit or otherwise disable any of it. This same information is available on numerous other websites and in various other (print, CD-ROM) media.

Please contact the FCC if you wish to change it or otherwise make it unavailable. 

## Choice/Opt-Out/Modify

This site gives members the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

**Email addresses**

As with most topics, be sure to see the FAQ pages for more info on email addresses.

Other than picking a username and a password for logging in, the only information that eHam.net requires for a user to become a "registered" member is a verified email address. Whenever a user enters a new email address, the user is emailed verification instructions. We require a validated email address to prevent registration abuse and so that certain functions like hints and resets for passwords will operate properly. The addresses are also used for automatic emails such as notifications that your submission (articles or strays) has been activated, and for features like classifieds that require, for example, buyers to get in touch with sellers. Email subscriptions to forums topics also require a valid email.

**Editing email addresses**

Log in, then go to your profile page, then click the basic user info link near the top.

**Hiding email addresses**

While email addresses are required for membership, users can opt to "hide" it from other users by going to their personal profile edit page, UN-checking the "Include your email..." box and **be sure** to click the "submit" button at the bottom.

NOTE: Even if you elect to "hide" your email address, it will still be viewable in any classified ads that you will place. This is to assure that others can contact those whom place ads.

**Other (non-email) information**

Logged-in users are always welcome to add or delete other information from their profile. 

## Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact the webmaster at the address at the bottom of every eham.net page.

or 

**eHam.net, LLC**  
PO Box 1334  
Aptos,CA  
95001
